<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Division App</string>
    
    
    <string name="Div1">Barisal was conquered by Muhammad bin Bakhtiyar Khalji and was later a significant territory of the Delhi Sultanate and Bengal Sultanate. After the decline of the Suri Empire, the territory became a semi-independent area in the Mughal period because of heavy fighting between the Muslims and Hindu chiefs, although most parts of the city were totally under the control of the governors of the proto-industrialised Bengal Subah. In course of time, it fell under the Bengal Nawabs. Raja Ramranjan Chakravarty was put as a de jure king during the Bengal Presidency of the British, later passed to East Pakistan at independence and finally Bangladesh.
    </string>


    <string name="Div2">Chittagong plays a vital role in the Bangladeshi economy. The Port of Chittagong, one of the world\'s oldest ports, whose coast appeared on Ptolemy world map, is the principal maritime gateway to the country. The port is the busiest international seaport on the Bay of Bengal and the third busiest in South Asia.[8] The Chittagong Stock Exchange is one of the country\'s two stock markets. Several Chittagong-based companies are among the largest industrial conglomerates and enterprises in Bangladesh. The port city is the largest base of the Bangladesh Navy and Bangladesh Coast Guard; while the Bangladesh Army and Bangladesh Air Force also maintains bases and contributes to the citys economy. Chittagong is the headquarters of the Eastern Zone of the Bangladesh Railway, having historically been the headquarters of British Indias Assam Bengal Railway and East Pakistans Pakistan Eastern Railway. A controversial ship breaking industry on the outskirts of the city, which supplies local steel but causes pollution, has come under international scrutiny.
    </string>

    <string name="Div3">Dhaka is the capital and the largest city of Bangladesh. It is the ninth-largest and the sixth-most densely populated city in the world, with a population of 8.9 million residents within the city limits, and a population of over 21 million residents in the Greater Dhaka Area. Dhaka is the economic, political and cultural center of Bangladesh. It is one of the major cities of South Asia, the largest city in Eastern South Asia and among the Bay of Bengal countries; and one of the largest cities among OIC countries. As part of the Bengal plain, the city is bounded by the Buriganga River, Turag River, Dhaleshwari River and Shitalakshya River. The city is located in an eponymous district and division.
    </string>

    <string name="Div4">Khulna  is the third largest city in Bangladesh. It is the administrative seat of Khulna District and Khulna Division. In the 2011 census, the city had a population of 663,342. The Khulna metropolitan area had an estimated population of 1.022 million in 2014.

Khulna is a port on the Rupsha and Bhairab Rivers. A hub of Bangladeshi industry, it hosts many national companies. Khulna is served by Port of Mongla (the second-largest seaport in the country), and is one of the two principal naval-command centres of the Bangladesh Navy. The navy base BNS Titumir is in the city.
</string>

    <string name="Div5">Mymensingh is the capital of Mymensingh Division of Bangladesh. The city is located on the Brahmaputra River, about 120 km  north of Dhaka the capital of the country. It is a major financial center and Educational district of North Central Bangladesh and the 4th largest city in Bangladesh. Border area cover Himalayan state of India, Gazipur District, Tangail District, Jamalpur District, Netrokona District, Kishoreganj District. Mymensingh is the 8th administrative divisional headquarter and 12th City corporation of Bangladesh. According to Ministry of Public Administration, Mymensingh is ranked 4th in district status. The density of Mymensingh city is 44,458/km2 which is the second most densely populated city in Bangladesh. Mymensingh attracts 25 percent of health tourists visiting Bangladesh. Mymensingh is the anglicised pronunciation of the original name Momenshahi, referring to a Muslim ruler called Shah Momin. Its elevation is over 19 m above sea level, the highest of Bangladesh major cities. Mymensingh related with old Brahmaputra river, handcrafted duvet called Nakshikantha (Bengali: নকশীকাঁথা) and a rural ballad called Maimansingha Gitika

</string>

    <string name="Div6">Rajshahi  historically Rampur Boalia; nicknamed Silk City or City of Education) is a metropolitan city, and a major urban, commercial and educational centre of Bangladesh. It is also the administrative seat of eponymous division and district. [note 1] Located on the north bank of the Padma River, near the Bangladesh-India border, the city has a population of over 763,952 residents.[4] The city is surrounded by the satellite towns of Nowhata and Katakhali, which together build an urban agglomeration of about 1 million population. Arguably Rajshahi is the most clean and green among the cities in Bangladesh.[5]

Modern Rajshahi lies in the ancient region of Pundravardhana. The foundation of the city dates to 1634, according to epigraphic records at the mausoleum of Sufi saint Shah Makhdum. The area hosted a Dutch settlement in the 18th century. The Rajshahi municipality was constituted during the British Raj in 1876. It was a divisional capital of the Bengal Presidency.
</string>

    <string name="Div7">Rangpur is one of the major cities in Bangladesh and Rangpur Division. Rangpur was declared a district headquarters on 16 December 1769, and established as a municipality in 1869, making it one of the oldest municipalities in Bangladesh. The municipal office building was erected in 1892 under the precedence Raja Janaki Ballav Sen. Chairman of the municipality. During the period of 1890, Shyamasundari canal was excavated for improvement of the town. Sharfuddin Ahmed Jhantu was 1st Mayor of Rangpur City Corporation.
    </string>

    <string name="Div8">Sylhet  is a metropolitan city in northeastern Bangladesh. It is the administrative seat of Sylhet Division. The city is located on the right bank of the Surma River in northeastern Bengal. It has a subtropical climate and lush highland terrain. The city has a population of more than half a million. Sylhet is one of most important spiritual and cultural centres. It is one of the most important cities of Bangladesh, after Dhaka and Chittagong due to its importance to the countrys economy. Sylhet produces the highest amount of tea and gas in the country.</string>

</resources>